[
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of HTML?",
      "options": ["To style web pages;", "To create the structure and content of web pages;", "To add interactivity to web pages;", "To write server-side code"],
      "answer": "To write server-side code"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which language is primarily used for styling web pages?",
      "options": ["HTML", "JavaScript", "CSS", "Python"],
      "answer": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": " Explain the concept of SEO (Search Engine Optimization)?",
      "options": ["The practice of optimizing websites to rank higher in search engine results", "The process of adding interactive features to a website", "The method of securing a website from cyber attacks", "The technique of compressing website files for faster loading"],
      "answer": "The practice of optimizing websites to rank higher in search engine results"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the `React Router` library?",
      "options": ["To handle events", " To fetch data ", "To manage state", " To handle client-side routing in a React application"],
      "answer": "To handle client-side routing in a React application"
    },
    {
      "question": " Which tag is used to define the title of a web page?",
      "options": [" <head> ", "<h1> ", " <body>", "<title>"],
      "answer": "<title>"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the <meta> tag?",
      "options": [
        "   To add JavaScript functionality",
        "To define styles for the web page ",
        "To create a hyperlink",
        "To provide metadata about the web page"
      ],
      "answer": "To provide metadata about the web page"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which tag is used to create an unordered list?",
      "options": [" <ul>", "<list>", "<li> ", "   <ol>"],
      "answer": " <ul>"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the <div> tag?",
      "options": [
        "  To add an image",
        "To create a division or section on a web page",
        "To create a hyperlink",
        "To define a heading"
      ],
      "answer": "To create a division or section on a web page"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which attribute is used to specify a unique identifier for an HTML element?",
      "options": [
        " id ",
        "class ",
        "Div",
        "style "
      ],
      "answer": "id"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the <form> tag?",
      "options": [
        " To create a table",
        "To add a video to the web page",
        "      To define a navigation menu",
        "    To create a form for user input"
      ],
      "answer": "To create a form for user input"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which input type is used for creating a checkbox?",
      "options": [
        " checkbox ;",
        "radio ;",
        " submit ;",
        " text;"
      ],
      "answer": "checkbox;"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the <label> tag within a form?",
      "options": ["To group related input fields", "To define a text input field", "To provide a label for an input field", "To create a submit button"],
      "answer": "To provide a label for an input field"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HTML tag is used to create a hyperlink?",
      "options": ["<a>", "<href>", "<link>", "<url>"],
      "answer": " <href>"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the <span> tag?",
      "options": [
        "To define a heading",
        "To add an image",
        "To create a division or section on a web page",
        "To create an inline container for text"
      ],
      "answer": "To create an inline container for text"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which tag is used to add an image to a web page?",
      "options": ["<img>", "<picture> ", "<image>", "<image>"],
      "answer": "<img>"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the alt attribute for images?",
      "options": ["To link the image to another web page", "To apply a filter to the image", "To define the size of the image", "To specify the alternative text for an image"],
      "answer": "To specify the alternative text for an image"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which HTML tag is used to create a semantic header section?",
      "options": [
        "<header>",
        "<head>",
        "<top> ",
        "<section>"
      ],
      "answer": "<header>"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the <meta name=(viewport)> tag ?",
      "options": ["To control the viewport on mobile devices for responsive design", "To define the character encoding of the document", "To create a navigation menu", "To link external JavaScript files "],
      "answer": "To control the viewport on mobile devices for responsive design"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which tag is used to create a semantic main content section?",
      "options": ["<main>", " <content>", "<article>", "<body>"],
      "answer": " <main>"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the required attribute do in an input field?",
      "options": [
        " It adds a tooltip to the input field",
        "It disables the input field",
        "It sets a default value for the input field ",
        " It makes the input field mandatory to fill"
      ],
      "answer": "It makes the input field mandatory to fill"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method joins all elements of an array into a string?",
      "options": [".join()", ".concat()", ".reduce()", ".map()"],
      "answer": ".join()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method can be used to find the largest number in an array?",
      "options": [
        "Math.max(...array)",
        "Math.max(array)",
        "Math.maximum(array)",
        "Math.maxAll(array)"
      ],
      "answer": "Math.max(...array)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method is used to stop an interval timer in JavaScript?",
      "options": [
        "clearInterval()",
        "stopInterval()",
        "clearTimer()",
        "stopTimer()"
      ],
      "answer": "clearInterval()"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the `typeof` operator return?",
      "options": [
        "The data type of the operand",
        "The length of the operand",
        "The value of the operand",
        "The name of the operand"
      ],
      "answer": "The data type of the operand"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which operator is used to assign a value to a variable in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["=", "==", "===", "!="],
      "answer": "="
    },
    {
      "question": "Which JavaScript method is used to select an HTML element by its ID?",
      "options": [
        "getElementById()",
        "getElementsByClassName()",
        "querySelector()",
        "getElementByTagName()"
      ],
      "answer": "getElementById()"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can you create an array in JavaScript?",
      "options": [
        "let arr = [];",
        "let arr = Array();",
        "let arr = new Array();",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a looping structure in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["for", "while", "foreach", "do-while"],
      "answer": "foreach"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following methods returns the number of milliseconds since 1 January 1970?",
      "options": [
        "Date.now()",
        "Date.getMilliseconds()",
        "Date.milliseconds()",
        "Date.time()"
      ],
      "answer": "Date.now()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method removes the first element from an array?",
      "options": [".shift()", ".unshift()", ".pop()", ".splice()"],
      "answer": ".shift()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method creates a new array with elements that pass a test?",
      "options": [".filter()", ".map()", ".reduce()", ".slice()"],
      "answer": ".filter()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which JavaScript method is used to write HTML content into an HTML element?",
      "options": [
        "innerHTML",
        "document.write()",
        "document.createElement()",
        "createElement()"
      ],
      "answer": "innerHTML"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid JavaScript keyword?",
      "options": ["let", "var", "function", "integer"],
      "answer": "integer"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you declare a constant in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["const", "let", "var", "constant"],
      "answer": "const"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will the following code output: `console.log([] + []);`?",
      "options": [
        "'' (an empty string)",
        "[] (an empty array)",
        "null",
        "undefined"
      ],
      "answer": "'' (an empty string)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which JavaScript keyword is used to check whether a condition is true or false?",
      "options": ["if", "for", "while", "switch"],
      "answer": "if"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method adds new items to the end of an array, and returns the new length?",
      "options": [".push()", ".pop()", ".shift()", ".unshift()"],
      "answer": ".push()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which event occurs when the user clicks on an HTML element?",
      "options": ["onchange", "onmouseover", "onmouseclick", "onclick"],
      "answer": "onclick"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you round the number 7.25 to the nearest integer?",
      "options": [
        "Math.round(7.25)",
        "round(7.25)",
        "Math.rnd(7.25)",
        "rnd(7.25)"
      ],
      "answer": "Math.round(7.25)"
    },
  
    {
      "question": "What will the following code output: `console.log('5' - 3);`?",
      "options": ["2", "'53'", "'5'", "undefined"],
      "answer": "2"
    },
  
    {
      "question": "Which keyword is used to declare a variable in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["let", "var", "const", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you check if a value is NaN in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["isNaN()", "typeof", "== NaN", "isNan()"],
      "answer": "isNaN()"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method is used to convert a string to a number in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["parseInt()", "parseFloat()", "Number()", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you add an element to the end of an array in JavaScript?",
      "options": [" array.add(element); ", "  array.push(element);", "  Both a and c ", " array[array.length] = element; "],
      "answer": "  Both a and c "
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of the `let` keyword in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["To declare a global variable", "To declare a block-scoped variable", " To declare a function", " To declare a constant variable"],
      "answer": " To declare a block-scoped variable "
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct way to define a function in JavaScript?",
      "options": [" function: myFunction() {}", " function myFunction() {}", " Both a and b", " var myFunction = function() {}"],
      "answer": "Both a and b"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will the following code output: `console.log(2 == '2');`?",
      "options": ["true", "false", "undefined", "NaN"],
      "answer": "true"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will be the output of the following code console.log(3 + 4)?",
      "options": [
        "7",
        "34",
        "6",
        " NaN"
      ],
      "answer": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a JavaScript data type?",
      "options": [" Array ", " Double", " Boolean", " Undefined"],
      "answer": " Double"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the output of the following code. (console.log(typeof null))?",
      "options": [
        "undefined",
        "object",
        "null",
        "Boolean"
      ],
      "answer": "object"
    }
  ]  